Finding Aid for the Harold Garfinkel Papers LSC.1273
UCLA Library Special Collections
Harold Garfinkel papers
1952-2007
UCLA Library Special Collections
Harold Garfinkel
LSC.1273
86.0 Linear Feet (160 boxes)
Harold Garfinkel was a professor of sociology at the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA) from 1954 to 1987. The papers include: materials relating to Garfinkel's study of correspondence received by California Governor Edmund G. (Pat) Brown regarding the criminal case of Caryl Chessman (executed on May 2, 1960) and issues regarding capital punishment; transcripts and audio recordings of UCLA course lectures by Garfinkel (Sociology Department); correspondence; speeches and presentations; reprints; research notes and data; and research proposals.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: This collection contains both processed and unprocessed audiovisual materials. Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access, unless otherwise noted in a Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note at the file level. All requests to access processed materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Professor Harold Garfinkel, 1981 and 2010.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942330613606533
Biography/History
Harold Garfinkel was the social theorist who developed and utilized ethnomethodology to study social thought and practice. He received a BS in economics from the University of Newark in 1939; an MA in sociology from the University of North Carolina in 1942; and a Ph.D in sociology from Harvard University in 1952. He worked as an assistant professor (1954-1957) and professor of sociology (1960-1984) at UCLA. He received the Cooley-Mead Award of the Social Psychology Section of the American Sociological Association in 1995. He wrote Studies in Ethnomethodology published in 1967.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of materials relating to a project to study the correspondence received by the Governor of California, about the case of Caryl Chessman, 1959-1960, and related issues such as capital punishment. Chessman was convicted on various felony counts and his execution on May 2, 1960 brought to an end court proceedings that had lasted over a period of years.
The original letters to the Governor are arranged in several numbered sequences: a detailed description of both the arrangement and the numbering system, which was set up by the Governor's Office and subsequently retained, is given in Box 2, as part of what appears to be a draft progress report dated September 12, 1962, on the study project.
Correspondence is selected (not all correspondence is included).
The addition to the Harold Garfinkel Papers was acquired between 2008-2010 and includes Garfinkel's professional and research files dating prior to and after Garfinkel's Chessman research; selected audio recordings; correspondence and printed email; typed transcriptions of course lectures and presentations; reprints; research notes; and research proposals.
Ethnomethodology: "refer[s] to the investigation of the rational properties of indexical expressions and other practical actions as contingent ongoing accomplishments of organized artful practices of everyday life."
Abbreviations used:
HG = Harold Garfinkel
NIMH = National Institute for Mental Health
NPI = Neuropsychiatric Institute (University of California, Los Angeles)
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence and other files re: project (Boxes 1-3).
Copies of case papers and court documents "Governor's Diary," 1959-60 (Box 4).
Card indexes re: project (Boxes 5-6).
Samples of original letters to California Governor re: Chessman case (Boxes 7-12).
Original letters to Governor Edmund G. (Pat) Brown (Boxes 13-148).
Related Material
An additional group of material, unconnected to the Chessman correspondence project and relating to a patient study conducted by the UCLA Neuropsychiatric Institute, has been transferred to UCLA University Archives Record Series 627.
SEE ALSO: Neuropsychiatric Institute (NPI). "Studies of Suitability for Psychiatric Outpatient Treatment" clinical study and survey by Harold Garfinkel. (UCLA University Archives Record Series 627).
Sociologists -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Garfinkel, Harold--Archives.; Chessman, Caryl; University of California, Los Angeles. Department of Sociology--Faculty -- Archives
- Correspondence & other files re project. (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3)
- Copies of case papers & court documents "Governors Diary,", 1959-1960; (2 binders) (Box 4)
- Various card indexes re project. (Box 5, Box 6)
- Samples of original letters to Governor of California re Chessman case [several sequences]. (Box 7, Box 8)
- Samples of original letters to Governor [one sequence]. (Box 9, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12)
- Original Letters to Governor
  - "Con ex,", 1959-1960
    - July 14-October 11, 1959., 1-176 (Box 13)
    - October 12 -13, 1959., 179-385 (Box 14)
    - October 12-13, 1959., 386-635 (Box 15)
    - October 14 -15, 1959., 637-961 (Box 16)
    - October 15-17, 1959., 962-1253 (Box 17)
    - October 17-19, 1959., 1267-1571 (Box 18)
    - October 19-21, 1959., 1572-1894 (Box 19)
    - October 21-November 12, 1959., 1896-2121 (Box 20)
    - November 13, 1950-January 9, 1960., 2122-2274 (Box 21)
    - January 10-29, 1960., 2275-2449 (Box 22)
    - January 29-31, 1960., 2450-2642 (Box 23)
    - February 1-4, 1960., 2647-2859 (Box 24)
    - February 4-8, 1960., 2860-3099 (Box 25)
    - February 8-10, 1960., 3100-3362 (Box 26)
    - February 10-12, 1960., 3363-3620 (Box 27)
    - February 12-13, 1960., 3623-3875 (Box 28)
    - February 14, 1960., 3880-4075 (Box 29)
    - February 15, 1960., 4076-4260 (Box 30)
    - February 15-16, 1960., 4261-4569 (Box 31)
    - February 16, 1960., 4571-4809 (Box 32)
    - February 16, 1960., 4810-5191 (Box 33)
    - February 17, 1960., 5192-5442 (Box 34)
    - February 17, 1960., 5443-5746 (Box 35)
    - February 17, 1960., 5747-6093 (Box 36)
    - February 17, 1960., 6094-6864 (Box 37)
    - February 18, 1960., 6865-7175 (Box 38)
    - February 18, 1960., 7176-8400 (Box 39)
    - February 18, 1960., 8401-9611 (Box 40)
    - February 18, 1960., 9612-10471 (Box 41)
    - February 19, 1960., 10472-10736 (Box 42)
    - February 19, 1960., 10737-10985 (Box 43)
    - February 19-20, 1960., 10986-11559 (Box 44)
    - February 20, 1960., 11560-11824 (Box 45)
    - February 20-21, 1960., 11825-12085 (Box 46)
    - February 21-22 1960., 12086-12320 (Box 47)
    - February 22, 1960., 12321-12555 (Box 48)
    - February 22, 1960., 12556-12853 (Box 49)
    - February 22-23, 1960., 12854-13136 (Box 50)
    - February 23-24, 1960., 13137-13411 (Box 51)
    - February 24, 1960., 13414-13691 (Box 52)
    - February 24-25, 1960., 13692-13956 (Box 53)
    - February 26, 1960., 13963-14275 (Box 54)
    - February 26-27, 1960., 14276-14552 (Box 55)
    - February 27-28, 1960., 14556-14870 (Box 56)
    - February 28-29, 1960., 14871-15136 (Box 57)
    - February 29-March 1, 1960., 15139-15460 (Box 58)
    - March 1-2, 1960., 15461-15757 (Box 59)
    - March 2-3, 1960., 15758-16056 (Box 60)
    - March 3, 1960., 16058-16332 (Box 61)
    - March 4-5, 1960., 16333-16655 (Box 62)
    - March 5-7, 1960., 16656-16933 (Box 63)
    - March 7-8, 1960., 16934-17222 (Box 64)
    - March 8-9, 1960., 17223-17541 (Box 65)
    - March 9-11, 1960., 17542-17859 (Box 66)
    - March 12-24, 1960., 17860-18063 (Box 67)
    - April 2-21, 1960., 18064-18283 (Box 68)
    - April 21-25, 1960., 18284-18526 (Box 69)
    - April 25-26, 1960., 18527-18825 (Box 70)
    - April 26, 1960., 18827-19072 (Box 71)
    - April 27, 1960., 19073-19280 (Box 72)
    - April 27, 1960., 19282-19593 (Box 73)
    - April 27-28, 1960., 19594-19839 (Box 74)
    - April 28-29, 1960., 19840-120182 (Box 75)
    - April 29, 1960., 120183-120687 (Box 76)
    - April 30-May 1, 1960., 120688-121557 (Box 77)
    - May 1-2, 1960; n.d., 121558-122388 (Box 78)
  - "Pro ex,", 1959-1960
    - October 10-19, 1959., 20001-20362 (Box 79)
    - October 19, 1959-January 30, 1960., 20364-20629 (Box 80)
    - January 30-February 9, 1960., 20630-20880 (Box 81)
    - February 10-16, 1960., 20881-21258 (Box 82)
    - February 16-17, 1960., 21259-21646 (Box 83)
    - February 18-19, 1960., 21648-21978 (Box 84)
    - February 19, 1960., 21980-22199 (Box 85)
    - February 19, 1960., 22200-22381 (Box 86)
    - February 19, 1960., 22382-22646 (Box 87)
    - February 19, 1960., 22647-22848 (Box 88)
    - February 19, 1960., 22849-23289 (Box 89)
    - February 20, 1960., 23290-23496 (Box 90)
    - February 20, 1960., 23497-23752 (Box 91)
    - February 20, 1960., 23753-24032 (Box 92)
    - February 20-21, 1960., 24033-24405 (Box 93)
    - February 21, 1960., 24406-24683 (Box 94)
    - February 21-22, 1960., 24684-24910 (Box 95)
    - February 22, 1960., 24911-25206 (Box 96)
    - February 22-23, 1960., 25207-25504 (Box 97)
    - February 23, 1960., 25505-25763 (Box 98)
    - February 23-24, 1960., 25764-26039 (Box 99)
    - February 24, 1960., 26040-26280 (Box 100)
    - February 24-25, 1960., 26281-26530 (Box 101)
    - February 26, 1960., 26531-26746 (Box 102)
    - February 26-27, 1960., 26747-27027 (Box 103)
    - February 27-March 1, 1960., 27028-27266 (Box 104)
    - March 1-3, 1960., 27267-27540 (Box 105)
    - March 3-6, 1960., 27541-27761 (Box 106)
    - March 7-8, 1960., 27763-28032 (Box 107)
    - March 8-11, 1960., 28033-28299 (Box 108)
    - March 11-17, 1960., 28301-28502 (Box 109)
    - March 17-25, 1960., 28504-28705 (Box 110)
    - March 26-April 8, 1960., 28706-28879 (Box 111)
    - April 9-19, 1960., 28900-29188 (Box 112)
    - April 19-May 1, 1960., 29189-29783 (Box 113)
    - May 2-5, 1960., 29784-30287 (Box 114)
    - October 8-13, 1959., 35005-35073 (Box 114)
    - October 14-15, 1959., 35074-35382 (Box 115)
    - October 15-17, 1959., 35383-35646 (Box 116)
    - October 17, 1959-April 26, 1960., 35647-35826 (Box 117)
    - April 26-28, 1960., 35827-36064 (Box 118)
    - April 28, 1960., 36065-36345 (Box 119)
    - April 28-29, 1960., 36346-36554 (Box 120)
    - April 29, 1960., 36555-36897 (Box 121)
    - April 29-30, 1960., 36898-37185 (Box 122)
    - April 30-May 24, 1960., 37187-37335 (Box 123)
  - "Pro & con ex,", October 12, 1959-February 18, 1960
    - October 12, 1959-February 18, 1960., 40001-40087 (Box 123)
    - February 19-20, 1960., 40088-40379 (Box 124)
    - February 21-26, 1960., 40380-40607 (Box 125)
    - February 27-29, 1960., 40608-40834 (Box 126)
    - March 1-15, 1960., 40835-41066 (Box 127)
    - March 18-April 27, 1960., 41067-41250 (Box 128)
    - April 28-May 2, 1960., 41251-41468 (Box 129)
    - October 18, 1959-February 19, 1960., 45001-45047 (Box 129)
    - February 19-27, 1960., 45049-45234 (Box 130)
    - February 28-April 18, 1960., 45235-45385 (Box 131)
    - Phone notes etc., & envelopes.", April 19-May 1, 1960.; 45386-45474 (Box 132)
  - "Cecil Poole,", 1960
    General note
    [Date of Chessman's execution - May 2]
    - May 2-3, 1960., 50001-50293 (Box 133)
    - May 3-18, 1960., 50294-50533 (Box 134)
    - n.d., 50535-50547 (Box 135)
  - "Dick Tuck,", 1960
    - February 7-March 3, 1960., 55001-55149 (Box 135)
    - March 3-April 16, 1960., 55150-55307 (Box 136)
  - "Foreign,", [n.d.]
    - A - Z., 60001-60213 (Box 137)
    - A - Cn., 65001-65999 (Box 137)
    - Co - Ir., 65100-65338 (Box 138)
    - It - Z., 65340-65597 (Box 139)
    - A - C., 70001-70234 (Box 140)
    - D - H., 70235-70553 (Box 141)
    - I - Po., 70554-70906 (Box 142)
    - Pu - Z., 70907-71121 (Box 143)
  - "786 petitions from the Los Angeles Times for clemency,", April 1960.; (Newsprint sheets in original envelopes) (Box 144, Box 145, Box 146, Box 147, Box 148)
- Clinic Study A., circa 1959-1960; 1 box of index cards (Box 149)
  Scope and Contents note
  Name cards, results, mail questions, procedures for clinical study.
- Miscellaneous audio recordings, circa 1959; 12 audio tape reels (7 inch reels) (Box 149)
  - HG I, 1959 January 20; yrlsc_1273_149_01a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:02:29) (Box 149, Case 1)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are available for access. All requests to access digital materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    Scope and Contents
    Transcribed from container: Reel No. 1 of 2. 1st and 2nd hours of 3
  - HG I, 1959 January 20; yrlsc_1273_149_01b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:04:04) (Box 149, Case 1)
  - HG II, 1959 January 20-31; yrlsc_1273_149_02a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:54:56) (Box 149, Case 2)
    Transcribed from container: Reel No. 2 of 2. 1/20/59- 3rd hour of 3. 1/31/59- 1st hour of 3
  - HG II, 1959 January 20-31; yrlsc_1273_149_02b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:04:05) (Box 149, Case 2)
  - HG III, 1959 January 31; yrlsc_1273_149_03a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:05:35) (Box 149, Case 3)
    Transcribed from container: Reel No. 1 of 1. 1/31/59- 2nd hour of 3 and 3rd hour of 3
  - HG III, 1959 January 31; yrlsc_1273_149_03b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:39:23) (Box 149, Case 3)
    Transcribed from container: Reel No. 1 of 1. 1/31/59- 2nd hour of 3 and 3rd hour of 4
  - HG IV, 1959 February 2-14; yrlsc_1273_149_04a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:00:45) (Box 149, Case 4)
    Transcribed from container: Reel No. 1 of 2. 2/7/59- 1st hour 1 hour + 60 of side 2. 2/14/59- from 65' to end of side 2 cont'd next reel tape 2
  - HG IV, 1959 February 2-14; yrlsc_1273_149_04b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:00:45) (Box 149, Case 4)
  - HG V, 1959 February 14; yrlsc_1273_149_05a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:45:43) (Box 149, Case 5)
    Transcribed from container: Reel No. 2 of 2. Cont'd from tape 1
  - HG V, 1959 February 28; yrlsc_1273_149_06a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:04:11) (Box 149, Case 6)
    Transcribed from container: Reel No. 1of 1. 2 hours
  - HG VI, 1959 February 28; yrlsc_1273_149_06b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:36:55) (Box 149, Case 6)
  - HG VII, 1959 April 11; yrlsc_1273_149_07a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:03:21) (Box 149, Case 7)
    Transcribed from container: Reel No. 1 of 2
  - HG VII, 1959 April 11; yrlsc_1273_149_07b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:03:17) (Box 149, Case 7)
    Transcribed from container: Reel No. 1 of 2. Side 1 only- 0-200" on Wollensak index
  - HG VIII, 1959 April 11; yrlsc_1273_149_08; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:20:13) (Box 149, Case 8)
  - HG IX, 1959 April 15; yrlsc_1273_149_09a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:00:46) (Box 149, Case 9)
    Transcribed from container: Reel No. 1 of 1
  - HG IX, 1959 April 15; yrlsc_1273_149_09b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:56:09) (Box 149, Case 9)
  - HG X, 1959 May 16; yrlsc_1273_149_10a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:04:31) (Box 149, Case 10)
    Transcribed from container: Reel No. 1 of 8
  - HG X, 1959 May 16; yrlsc_1273_149_10b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:15:02) (Box 149, Case 10)
- Sex control group. Book I and Book II., computer printouts (Box 149)
- Clinical study: reliability., circa 1959-1965; 5 folders (Box 150)
  Includes keypunch card count sheets; notes on IBM and Unisort computer programs; clinical study rules.
  Full title of clinical study: Studies of Suitability for Psychiatric Outpatient Treatment; study conducted at the UCLA Neuropsychiatric Institute/NPI.
- Miscellaneous audio recordings., circa 1960-1975; 42 audio tape reels (7 inch reels) (Box 150)
  Includes: Ethnomethodology seminar, 1963; Wed[nesday] Group, 1965 December; Bittner, 1972 [lecture]; Pollner, 1972 [lecture]; Sacks, 1972 [lecture].
  - HG XI, 1959 June 27; yrlsc_1273_150_002a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:04:53) (Box 150, Case 2)
    Transcribed from container: Duplicate 14
  - HG XI, 1959 June 27; yrlsc_1273_150_002b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:33:01) (Box 150, Case 2)
  - HG XII, 1959 July 28; yrlsc_1273_150_003; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 0:58:38) (Box 150, Case 3)
    Transcribed from container: Duplicate 16. Reel #171 (side one only used)
  - Ethnomethodology Seminar, 1963 December 10; yrlsc_1273_150_004a; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:04:19) (Box 150, Case 4)
    Transcribed from container: #1 of 2
  - Ethnomethodology Seminar, 1963 December 10; yrlsc_1273_150_004b; 1 Sound Recordings (1 1/4 inch audiotape; Duration: 1:02:15) (Box 150, Case 4)
    Transcribed from container: #1 of 3
- Sociology 251. Ethnomethodology seminar., 1962 September - 1963 June; 22 folders (Box 151)
  Typed transcriptions of course lectures; transcriptions edited by Harold Garfinkel.
- Sociology 251. Ethnomethodology seminar. Reading signs., 1963 September - December; 6 folders (Box 151)
  Typed transcriptions of course lectures; transcriptions edited by Harold Garfinkel; includes transcriptions of a seminar discussion on the assassination of U.S. President John F. Kennedy (November 1963)
- Sociology 251. Ethnomethodology seminar., 1964 February - May; 9 folders (Box 151)
- Clinical study: reliability., circa 1959-1965; files and 2 audio reels (Box 152)
  Includes transcripts of Harold Garfinkel and study staff discussing design and implementation; documentation on coding of study results; code books; audio recordings.
- H.G. and Harvey Sacks publications and presentations, 1967, 1969; 1 folder (Box 152)
- H.G. presentations and publications, 1958 November 25, n.d. (Box 152)
- 16th Annual Conference on World Affairs (University of Colorado, Boulder, CO)., 1963 April 11-12; 1 folder (Box 153)
  Partially edited transcripts of talks delivered by Egon Bittner, Harold Garfinkel, and Harvey Sacks. Includes: Mocking up the rules of everyday activity (Garfinkel); More on mock-ups (Sacks); Reasonable accounts (Garfinkel); Ethical symbols (Bittner); Rose and Sacks on translations.
- Edward Rose and Harold Garfinkel. Talks in Boulder [Colorado]., 1963 October 15-16 (Box 153)
  Typed transcript.
- MacArthur, Nancy., 1967; typed transcripts (Box 153)
- Open colloquium summer session, Boston University., 1975 June-July; 9 folders (Box 153)
  Typed transcripts. Seminar topics include: Maxims and studies - three glosses; Mundane accountable structure of lectures; Queue structures; Building a series of comparison policies; Unique adequacy; Kid's talk; Natural availability of order.
- Predicting the effects of time and rate of supervisory succession upon group performance., 1953 June (Box 153)
  Research proposal abstract to Personnel Research Board, [Harvard University?].
- Seminar in Sociology. (Department of Psychiatry, UCLA School of Medicine.), 1957 Fall; 3 folders (Box 153)
  Course files and related bibliographies.
- Sociology 172. Contemporary sociological theorizing - Parsons., 1963 February-May; 23 folders (Box 153)
- Sociology 179. Study of Norms., 1966 February - June; .25 linear ft. (Box 153)
  Typed transcripts of class discussions.
- Sociology 251. Social maladjustment: sociology of mental disorder., 1957 Spring; 1 folder (Box 153)
- Sociology 251. Topics in problems of social order: rational actions., 1964 September - 1965 January; 12 folders (Box 153)
  Typed transcripts.
- The Alligator Episode., 1975-1976; black/white photograph contact prints (Box 153)
  Transcription of "Alligator" and related photographs.
  Relates to Garfinkel's public lectures: "On the study of naturally organized activities" (Boston University, Summer 1975) and "An introduction for novices to the study of naturally organized activities" (New York University, November 1976). Also referenced in "Studies of Kids' Culture and Kids' Talk" by Garfinkel, George Girton, Eric Livingston, and Harvey Sacks.
- Articles, conference handouts, preprints., 1977-1998; 16 folders (Box 154)
  Selected articles, etc. NOT authored by Harold Garfinkel.
- Correspondence., 1950-1999; 18 folders (Box 154)
  Includes: selected professional correspondence, memos; UCLA correspondence, memos. Arranged chronologically.
- Research proposals, publishing proposals., 1956-1965; 1 folder (Box 154)
  Proposals submitted by Garfinkel. Includes 1956 National Institute of Mental Health/NIMH Senior Fellowship proposal.
- American Sociological Review., 1960; 1962-1965 (Box 155)
  Includes Garfinkel's referee reviews of submitted manuscripts.
- Barak, Henry., no date (Box 155)
  Transcripts (draft with edits and final).
- Boder, David P., 1957; 2 folders (Box 155)
  Includes index to "Topical autobiographies of displaced people," (Los Angeles, 1957); mimeograph copy with Garfinkel(?) edits, "Tale of Anna Kovitzka," n.d.
  David P. Boder, Research Associate/UCLA Department of Psychology, 1952-1962.
- Conference. Garfinkel and Howard Schwartz., 1967 July 22; 1967 June 17 (Box 155)
- Driscoll, James Patrick., 1968-1969 (Box 155)
  Includes copy of Driscoll's San Francisco State College Master's Thesis, "The Transsexuals" (1968 September).
- Eglin, Trent and Joan Sacks., 1967 May 15 (Box 155)
  Mimeograph notes on 'Citation Study.'
- Esken, Vicki., 1967 February 22; 1 folder; 1 reel audio tape (5") (Box 155)
  Harold Garfinkel's notes
- Kairath, Judy., 1963 May 21 (Box 155)
  Typed transcript about Lysergic acid (LSD); includes Harold Garfinkel note on Carlos Castaneda. File also labeled: Sociology 251.
- Massachusetts Mental Health Center. Department of Mental Health / Harvard Medical School. Department of Psychiatry. Research Training Program in Social Psychiatry., 1967 September - 1968 March (Box 155)
  Eilliott G. Mishler, Program Director.
- Provo [provocateur] materials., 1967 (Box 155)
  Includes issues of the publications: "Provo: the Underground Tab" (1967 June); "Provo: the Guardian of Morals" (1967 September). Seven issues of miscellaneous Los Angeles, California independent newspapers dating from 1967; black/white photographic snapshots of the Free Press Bookstore (Los Angeles, 1967 February); photocopies; news clippings.
  Provo is an abbreviation of 'provocateur.'
- Psychiatry, Department of (UCLA). (Box 155)
  Includes memos, seminar schedules.
- Purdue Conference (2nd Purdue Conference)., 1967 May 8 (Box 155)
  Transcripts of presentations by Kathy Crittendon, Richard J. Hill, and Harold Garfinkel.
- Queues., 1969 April 4 (Box 155)
  Harold Garfinkel's mimeograph notes.
- Quint, Jeanne C., R.N., 1960-1963 (Box 155)
  Includes: Quint's paper entitled 'Radical Mastectomy;' correspondence between Quint and Garfinkel.
- Simko, Maryann and Alberta [Simko?]. "Lies.", 1968 September 18 (Box 155)
  Transcript of interview by Harold Garfinkel.
- Sociology 148. Normal Environments., 1969 January (Box 155)
- Sociology 149. A Study of Norms., 1974 April to June; 12 folders (Box 155)
- Sociology 178. Normal Environments., 1965 October - 1966 January; 24 folders (Box 155)
- Sociology 181. Sociopathic Behavior., 1960 September (Box 155)
  Course related information; includes typed carbon copy of paper by Edward J. Kollar (UCLA Department of Psychiatry), "Psychological stress..."
- Sociology, Department of (UCLA)., 1962-1978 (Box 155)
- SPC phone calls., 1963 (Box 155)
  Handwritten index cards about phone calls.
- Thesis seminar. Garfinkel and Don Zimmerman., 1965 April (Box 155)